# Benjamin Higgins

Lewisburg, Pennsylvania, United States



higginsb2020@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ben-higgins-me

## Summary

Graduated from The Catholic University of America with a degree in mechanical engineering in May of 2020. Since then, I have started working at General Motors, pursuing a career in software development/engineering. I have now worked in the field for about 3 years.

I gained proficiency in Java, Android Development, and Gradle. In addition to career experience, I have since published apps on Google Play, built and published Websites using JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS.

As a Software Engineer my responsibilities include, defect analysis, building new functionality, and delivering updates to app design/function.

Most notably, I have developed solutions for critical launch defects, authored major app rework, deployed build pipeline updates, and mentored new engineers.

### **Experience**



### Software Engineer - Android App Developer

**General Motors** 

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

## Android Software Developer - Global Product Group Engineering Track at General

**General Motors** 

Jul 2021 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Worked in SAFe (Certified) Framework, as a software developer across several android apps.

Contributed to theming changes for Corvette, Cadillac, Chevy, and more brands.

Developed features, added functionality, and resolved defects and bugs for front-end and back-end applications within android studio, via Java and Kotlin.

Authored Espresso and Unit Test cases for both front-end and back-end applications.

Earned Design For Six Sigma Black Belt, as a project leader, comparing the business decision for developing new applications, outsourcing vs in-house development.

Preformed QA work for other developer changes.

### Software Integration Engineer - Global Product Group Engineering Track at **General Motors**

#### **General Motors**

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021 (8 months)

Within Agile Framework, worked as software integration engineer for the Google Assistant Services Team. Contributed to weekly software builds/releases.

Worked on regression and score-card testing for GAS applications on GM hardware.

Troubleshot and calibrated GM hardware.

Analyzed and tested defects from GAS, determined whether bugs were resulting from GM software/ hardware or Google software.

Interfaced with Google teams to resolve google related bugs.

Helped implement new features on GM Hardware.

### Controls Engineer - Global Product Group Engineering Track

**General Motors** 

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 (7 months)

Hybrid Optimization Tool, worked on the logic development for a MATLAB based engineering software tool to calculate fuel economy.

TCC optimization, calibrated torque limits and shift map for second gear fireing fraction based on vehicle response. Additionally, tested the cFTP City cycles to determine fuel economy savings, using the TCC calibrations.

#### **Education**



#### The Catholic University of America

Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering 2016 - 2020

### **Licenses & Certifications**



SAFe 5 Practitioner Certification - Scaled Agile, Inc.

64278996-6807



Certified SAFe® 5 Practitioner - Scaled Agile, Inc.

### **Skills**

Microsoft Office • Microsoft Excel • Microsoft Word • Microsoft PowerPoint • System Dynamics • Differential Equations • Fluid Mechanics • Thermodynamics • Research • Python (Programming Language)